Guide to the Fred B. Millett World War II Letters from Students, 1913, 1939 - 1948
Fred B. Millett World War II Letters from Students, 1913, 1939 - 1948
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Millett, Fred Benjamin, 1890-
1000-30
0.75
2
Fred B. Millett (1890-1976) was a professor of English and director of the Honors College at Wesleyan University.
The Fred Millet World War II Letters from Students were sent from both Wesleyan and non-Wesleyan students involved in the war effort. Although the collection does not contain Millett's responses, the letters reveal much about the lives of the young men during the war.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Donated by Patricia Millett, 1976.
Biographical Note
Fred B. Millett (1890-1976) was a professor of English and director of the Honors College at Wesleyan University. He received his bachelor's degree from Amherst College and a Ph.D. from the University of Chicago. Prior to coming to Wesleyan in 1937, he taught at Carnegie Tech, Queen's University in Ontario, and the University of Chicago. Millett taught at Wesleyan from 1937 until 1958. He was the author of a number of books and a frequent lecturer on literature and scholarship.
Collection Overview
The Fred B. Millet World War II Letters from Students were sent from both Wesleyan and non-Wesleyan students involved in the war effort. Although the collection does not contain Millett's letters, the students' letters reveal much about the lives of the young men during the war. They were apparently written in response to Millett's occasional personal newsletter for Wesleyan servicemen.
The collection also includes two newspapers related to the end of the war in 1945.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by last name of student. If a Wesleyan year of graduation was found, this is noted.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.; World War, 1939-1945 --Personal narratives, American.; Millett, Fred Benjamin, 1890-
Related Material
Fred Millett Papers, Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Ackart, Robert C., Class of 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albrecht, Gilbert P., Class of 1948 (Folder 2)
  - Aronson, Louis, Class of 1940 (Folder 3)
  - Atkinson, Frank G. Jr., Class of 1941 (Folder 4)
  - Augenblick, Richard G., Class of 1941 (Folder 5)
  - Babbit, C. Stephen Jr., Class of 1943 (Folder 6)
  - Bailey, Robert G., Class of 1932 (Folder 7)
  - Bangs, Laurence C. Jr., Class of 1942 (Folder 8)
  - Baudet, Pierre S. (Folder 9)
  - Bayard, James A., Class of 1943 (Folder 10)
  - Blumenthal, George, Class of 1949 (Folder 11)
  - Bower, John L., Class of 1946 (Folder 12)
  - Bowersox, Hermann C., Class of 1942 (Folder 13)
  - Brown, Lewis D. (Folder 14)
  - Buffham, Benson K., Class of 1941 (Folder 15)
  - Burks, J. C. Jr. (Folder 16)
  - Charlton, Quentin, Class of 1941 (Folder 17)
  - Clark, David R., Class of 1942 (Folder 18)
  - Cook, Robert P. Jr., Class of 1949 (Folder 19)
  - Curl, Peter V., Class of 1943 (Folder 20)
  - Curts, Holroyd B., Class of 1940 (Folder 21)
  - Davis, Preston Jr., Class of 1941 (Folder 22)
  - Decker, Charles (Folder 23)
  - Delman, John L. (Folder 24)
  - Dorchester, Douglas F., Class of 1946 (Folder 25)
  - Eisendratn, J., Class of 1940 (Folder 26)
  - Eckblaw, Walter E., Class of 1941 (Folder 27)
  - Eldridge, Donald A., Class of 1931 (Folder 28)
  - Ellis, William D., Class of 1941 (Folder 29)
  - Everett, George T., Class of 1942 (Folder 30)
  - Fash, William G., Class of 1939 (Folder 31)
  - Fertman, Donald G., Class of 1942 (Folder 32)
  - Fiess, Edward (Folder 33)
  - Ford, Philip, Class of 1940 (Folder 34)
  - Fox, Anderson, Class of 1942 (Folder 35)
  - Fretwell, Elbert K., Class of 1944 (Folder 36)
  - Gelblum, Morris R., Class of 1943 (Folder 37)
  - Grunbaum, Adolph, Class of 1944 (Folder 38)
  - Hammerstrom, Bryn, Class of 1939 (Folder 39)
  - Hastings, Edward H., Class of 1946 (Folder 40)
  - Haward, Douglas W., Class of 1941 (Folder 41)
  - Heironimus, Walter W., Class of 1942 (Folder 42)
  - Hillman, William P. Jr., Class of 1944 (Folder 43)
  - Hoffman, Arthur W., Class of 1942 (Folder 44)
  - Holton, Gerald, Class of 1941 (Folder 45)
  - Hoskins, Herbert W. Jr., Class of 1941 (Folder 46)
  - Huth, Edward J., Class of 1945 (Folder 47)
  - Johnson, Ralph R. Jr., Class of 1946 (Folder 48)
  - Keefe, Frederick L., Class of 1937 (Folder 49)
  - Kennedy, Robert C., Class of 1942 (Folder 50)
  - Kezerian, Stephen A., Class of 1944 (Folder 51)
  - Kilbon, Kenyon, Class of 1938 (Folder 52)
  - Knapp, Edgar H., Class of 1938 (Folder 53)
  - Koller, Ray W. (Folder 54)
  - Lord, Andrew J., Class of 1943 (Folder 55)
  - Lutwack, Leonard I., Class of 1939 (Folder 56)
  - MacCracken, James I., Class of 1944 (Folder 57)
  - Martin, Lewis B., Class of 1941 (Folder 58)
  - McGlynn, Robert W., Class of 1943 (Folder 59)
  - Meyer, Robert, Class of 1942 (Folder 60)
  - Miller, David L., Class of 1947 (Folder 61)
  - Montkawsher, Joseph M. (Folder 62)
  - Murray, Richard F., Class of 1949 (Folder 63)
  - Neuffer, Robert P. (Folder 64)
  - Newman, Walter (Folder 65)
  - Nichols, J. Alden, Class of 1949 (Folder 66)
  - Paterson, Arthur E. Jr., Class of 1943 (Folder 67)
  - Potter, Allen M., Class of 1947 (Folder 68)
  - Potter, James L., Class of 1944 (Folder 69)
  - Powers, John W., Class of 1942 (Folder 70)
  - Raleigh, John H., Class of 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Randall, A. E. Jr. (Folder 2)
  - Reynolds, John P., Class of 1940 (Folder 3)
  - Richards, Benjamin A., Class of 1942 (Folder 4)
  - Sampson, George H., Class of 1949 (Folder 5)
  - Sandahl, Eric P., Class of 1947 (Folder 6)
  - Severn, Cy (Folder 7)
  - Simpson, Robert, Class of 1943 (Folder 8)
  - Skinner, John W., Class of 1942 (Folder 9)
  - Smith, David J., Class of 1943 (Folder 10)
  - Stallman, Robert (Folder 11)
  - Staples, Hugh B., Class of 1944 (Folder 12)
  - Stevens, Carlton H. Jr., Class of 1940 (Folder 13)
  - Stillwell, William S., Class of 1939 (Folder 14)
  - Sutton, William A., Class of 1946 (Folder 15)
  - Symonds, Merrill A., Class of 1941 (Folder 16)
  - Toner, Walter J., Class of 1942 (Folder 17)
  - Vosburgh, Frank J. Jr., Class of 1942 (Folder 18)
  - White, Myron E., Class of 1941 (Folder 19)
  - Wilding, George H. II, Class of 1944 (Folder 20)
  - Williams, Talcott, Class of 1940 (Folder 21)
  - Wilson, U. Adrian, Class of 1945 (Folder 22)
  - Woodbridge, Dana M., Class of 1939 (Folder 23)
  - Woodward, Sheldon C., Class of 1942 (Folder 24)
  - Yocum, Trell W. II, Class of 1948 (Folder 25)
  - Zahnke, Laurence E., Class of 1942 (Folder 26)
  - Newspapers, 1945 (Folder 27)